Chris Merritt

Software Developer

Contact

Address

Tomball, TX, 77375

Phone

(832) 964-9608

E-mail

Christopher.aa.merritt@gmail.

com

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/merritt-christopher/

Skills

JavaScript

Very Good

HTML

Excellent

Troubleshooting

Very Good

CSS

Very Good

Java EE

Very Good

MySQL

Good

Spring

Full-stack Web Developer and Army Veteran with experience in troubleshooting technical issues and creative problem-solving. Detail-oriented, organized and meticulous employee. Works at fast pace to meet tight deadlines. Enthusiastic team player ready to contribute to company success.

Work History

2019-02 -2022-03

Diesel Technician, Co-Foreman

Texas State Rentals, Tomball, TX

- Organized the daily work schedule for the service team and ran the inspection team for sold equipment
- Established a new inspection procedures for company, resulting in a top sales award for Texas
- Trained, tested, and became the only AED-certified mechanic in the shop
- Troubleshot systems, traced problems and diagnosed root causes.

2010-08 -2015-06

91B Wheeled Vehicle Mechanic

US Army, JBLM, Washington

- Performed semi-annual and annual unscheduled services on light and heavy wheeled vehicles.
- Supervised and mentored 6 team members and oversaw daily service operations.
- Assessed vehicles to identify degree of malfunction or damage.
- Performed wheeled vehicle recovery operations.

Education

No Degree: Full Stack Web Development

Codeup - San Antonio, TX

A fully-immersive, project-based, and intensive 20-week Full-Stack Java Career Accelerator that provides students with 670 hours of expert instruction in software development

No Degree: Science

Lonestar Community College - Tomball, TX

- Dean's List 1st year 2016-2017
- finished 3 semesters toward an associates degree in

Object-Oriented Programming

Excellent

JQuery

Very Good

Development Projects

BudgetPros

Paired Program - BudgetPros is a site that aids users in becoming more conscious of their spending, and helps them organize their transactions. The profile page contains a list of all of your transactions along with a calculated account balance, a list of created savings goals, your budget expenses, and the total amount of money spent on non-budget expenses. Through the use of Spring Boot, Thymeleaf, and JavaScript our views are dynamic and user friendly. Using modals we cut down on the amount of pages needed to support our CRUD functions. The layout and styling of all pages were created through a combination of Bootstrap and CSS.

Outdoor Lister

Paired Program - Outdoor Lister is a resource for individuals who love everything outdoors to share and advertise events going on around them. Visitors can observe a list of events created by users from a wide variety of categories, and as a user you can create posts and share information with your community. The Outdoor Lister UI is built with a series of servlets and JSPs, and was created overall following the MVC process. Our goal was to create a user friendly site, and through our use of JSTL we were able to make more dynamic pages. We used JAVA on the backend paired with mySQL to send and receive the data needed to support all CRUD functionality.